dundas.com 2019-08-20

# Privacy Policy - Dundas Data Visualization

Last Updated: August 09, 2018

####  Philosophy Surrounding Privacy 

We, at Dundas Data Visualization, Inc. ("Dundas", "we" or "us"), value the trust that you have shown in our business and, in turn, we are committed to maintaining the accuracy, confidentiality, and security of your personal data. To that end, we have adopted this privacy policy (the “Policy”). 

This Policy explains how Dundas collects, uses, discloses and safeguards the personal data provided to us either directly by you or by a third party. It also describes your choices regarding use, access, and correction of your personal data.

By providing personal data to us or authorizing a third party to provide your personal data to us, you signify your consent to Dundas' collection, use and disclosure of your personal data in accordance with this Policy.

For purposes of this Policy, "personal data" shall mean any information or data relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. A person is considered identifiable if they can be identified directly, or indirectly, by reference to an identification number or to one or more factors that indicate their identity.

As part of our commitment to treat your personal data with respect, we operate in accordance with the following ten principles (the "Principles"): 

  * **Principle 1 – Accountability.**  We will maintain and protect the personal data under our control. We have designated an individual or individuals who is/are accountable for compliance with the Principles.
  * **Principle 2 – Identifying Purposes.**  The purposes for which personal data is collected by us will be identified to you before or at the time the information is collected. 
  * **Principle 3 – Consent.**  Except where required or permitted by law your informed consent is required for our collection, use or disclosure of your personal data. 
  * **Principle 4 – Limiting Collection.**  The personal data collected by us shall be limited to those details necessary for the purposes identified to you. ;
  * **Principle 5 – Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention.**  We will only use or disclose your personal data in accordance with the purposes for which it was originally collected unless you have otherwise consented, or when it is required or permitted by law. We will retain your personal data only for so long as is required to fulfill the purpose for which it was collected or as required by law. 
  * **Principle 6 – Accuracy.**  We shall make every reasonable effort to ensure your personal data is maintained in an accurate, complete and up-to-date form. 
  * **Principle 7 – Safeguarding Customer Information.**  We shall utilize no less than industry standards security safeguards to protect your personal data. 
  * **Principle 8 – Openness.**  If you would like a copy of our privacy policies we would be more than happy to provide one to you and if you have any questions regarding same, we are more than happy to discuss the merits with you. 
  * **Principle 9 – Customer Access.**  Upon your request, we shall inform you of: (i) the type of personal data we have collected; (ii) how we have used your personal data in the past, and how we may in the future; and (iii) whether or not we have disclosed your personal data to any third parties (and, if so, to whom). Individuals may verify the accuracy and completeness of their personal data, and may request that it be amended, if appropriate.   
Please note that before we are able to provide you with any information or correct any inaccuracies we may ask you to verify your identity and to provide other details to help us to respond to your request.
  * **Principle 10 – Handling Customer Complaints and Suggestions.**  Customers may direct any questions or enquiries with respect to the Principles or about our information handling practices by contacting: 

**Dundas Data Visualization, Inc.** 500 – 250 Ferrand Drive  
Toronto, ON, Canada  
M3C 3G8  
Phone: [+1-416-467-5100](tel:+14164675100)  
Fax: [+1-416-422-4801](tel:+14164224801)  
Email: [privacy@dundas.com](mailto:privacy@dundas.com)

#### Why We Gather Personal Information:

At Dundas, we gather and use personal data to process your orders for the purchase of software licenses, services and other products from Dundas, to facilitate and ensure the delivery of products purchased and services requested and to process payment of such orders. We also use the personal data you have provided to us to communicate with you about your purchases, to respond to any inquiries you make, to manage your account, give you access to support, free trials and the Dundas BI e-Learning courses and safeguard our respective interests. We will send you important notices, and respond to any special needs or enquiries you may have. We may also send you information about other products and services in which we believe you may be interested. 

We only use personal data for the purposes that we have disclosed to you. If for any reason your information is required to fulfill a different purpose, we will obtain your consent before we proceed. 

#### INFORMATION PROVIDED TO DUNDAS

Information in Dundas BI Support is entered by you when setting up your account. To use Dundas BI Support, you or another representative from your organization must set up a Dundas BI Support account and provide us with certain information such as your name, position/title, company name, company email address, company mailing address and applicable phone number. Typically, businesses are the ones who purchase our licenses and services. However, on the rare occasion, an individual may purchase a license or service for personal use, or an individual may use their own credit card (and not the business's credit card) or otherwise submit their own information instead of the business's information, to place an order or communicate with us. In those instances, their personal data may be collected. The type of personal data we may ask for depends on and is related to the reason (or purpose) such personal data was provided to us. For instance, in order to process and deliver orders for products and services purchased or requested from Dundas, we will collect your name, credit card information, email address and other similar pieces of information related to the individual purchasing the order. In addition to the foregoing, we may ask for company name, mailing address and applicable telephone numbers. 

We may gather such personal data from you via mail, email, facsimile, Internet, in person, over the telephone, or from third parties who we reasonably believe have your authority to disclose such personal data to us. 

If you submit your personal data through our website, we use your personal data to provide and support the interactive features you are seeking to use and to generally improve our products and services. Such support may include technical notices, updates, security alerts, and administrative messages. Where permitted by applicable law, we may also send you promotional communications from time to time to inform you of our products and services. These communications may include feature updates, surveys, newsletters, offers, contests and events. You can opt out of marketing communications at any time by contacting us at: [info@dundas.com](mailto:info@dundas.com?subject=Unsubscribe) with Unsubscribe in the subject line or following the unsubscribe link or opt-out instructions included in our marketing communications.

The choice to provide us with your personal data, either directly or through a third party, is always yours. However, your decision to withhold particular information may result in limiting our ability to provide you with the services or products you requested. 

#### DUNDAS' WEBSITE

We may also collect personal data from our website when you use the interactive features of the website, such as free trials, the Dundas BI e-Learning courses, surveys, contests, or promotions. If you apply for a position with Dundas through a job posting on our website, we will collect personal data about you such as your name, resume, phone number, and email address. If you comment on articles or blog posts, we may also collect certain personal data about you that you include in your comment. We and our authorized partners may also collect information using cookies for a variety of reasons. 

Through the use of website cookies (very small text file that is added to your hard drive from a web page), we monitor the ads you see and the number of times these ads are seen. Cookies are stored in your browser’s file directory. Next time you visit the site, your browser will read the cookie and relay the information back to the website. By using Dundas website you consent to the use of these cookies. 

COOKIES

DEFAULT EXPIRATION TIME

DESCRIPTION

Pardot (Salesforce)

default expiration: 10 years 

description: The visitor cookie is composed of a unique visitor ID and the unique identifier for your account. For example, the cookie name “visitor_id12345” stores the visitor value “1010101010”, and “12345” is the account identifier. This cookie is set for visitors by the Pardot tracking code.

If your account tracks opt-in preferences, the pi_opt_in cookie is set with a true or false value when the visitor opts in or out of tracking. More information on the cookies set by Pardot (Salesforce) and how to opt out are on the Pardot (Salesforce) website: <https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/>. 

AddSearch (3rd party)

default expiration: 2 years

description: Used to recognize browser type and version for purposes such as saving preferences (search term) and delivering relevant content. More information on the cookies set by AddSearch and how to opt out are on the AddSearch website.

Bombora (3rd party)

session-only

description: Used to collect information in either an aggregate form to help understand how websites are being used or to determine the effectiveness of marketing campaigns. More information on the cookies set by Bombora and how to opt out are on the [Bombora](https://bombora.com/privacy/cookie-statement) website.

1\. Google Analytics (1st party)

_ga

default expiration: 2 years

description: Used to distinguish users. The first task Google Analytics performs on a Web page is to write a new _ga cookie to identify the user as unique. If the _ga cookie already exists in that browser for the given site, the Google Analytics instead refreshes the expiration for a full two years.

_gid

default expiration: 24 hours

description: Used to distinguish users

_gat

default expiration: 1 minute 

description: Used to throttle request rate. If Google Analytics is deployed via Google Tag Manager, this cookie will be named _dc_gtm_

_gac

default expiration: 90 days

description: Contains campaign related information for the user. Google Ads website conversion tags will read this cookie unless you opt out. Learn more [here](https://privacy.google.com/#_ga=2.129505422.321627752.1533209074-293734585.1509986970). 

Cookies facilitate multi-session analysis if visitors do not delete cookies from their browsers. Similarly, a single individual who visits Dundas website using multiple browsers (Firefox and Chrome, for example) will be tracked in Google Analytics as multiple separate users, as will one person who accesses your site on multiple devices. If a visitor accesses Dundas website in a private/incognito browser window, Google Analytics will still track activity during the session, but the _ga cookie will not persist past the session. Any return visit will therefore be attributed to a new user. 

More information on Google Analytics cookies can be found [here](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage).

2\. Google Ad Manager (DoubleClick)

3rd party

default expiration: 18 months

description: Google Ad Manager (DoubleClick) sends a cookie to the browser when a user visits a page that shows Google Ad Manager (DoubleClick) ads. Pages with Google Ad Manager (DoubleClick) ads include ad tags that instruct browsers to request ad content from servers. When the server delivers the ad content, it also sends a cookie. But a page doesn’t have to show Google Ad Manager (DoubleClick) ads for this to happen; it just needs to include Google Ad Manager (DoubleClick) ad tags, which might load a click tracker or impression pixel instead. 

More information on the cookies set by Google Ad Manager (DoubleClick) and how to opt out are on the Google Ad Manager website: <https://admanager.google.com/home/>

We use both first and third party cookies from Google to inform and improve our advertising. Google may place further cookies, and the names of those cookies may change from time to time. You can opt out of these cookies by controlling your advertising preferences with Google. 

We use these cookies to measure users’ behavior to better develop our Products and Services. By using analytics services provided by third parties such as Google Analytics, we can analyze and measure which pages are viewed and how long for and which links are followed. We can use this information to provide more content which is of interest. We also use this analysis to report on our performance. 

OPT OUT OF COOKIES: Safari, Google Chrome, Internet Explorer and Edge or Mozilla Firefox. 

For questions, please contact: [marketing@dundas.com](mailto:privacy@dundas.com)

Dundas’ website includes social media features such as “Like” and “Share” buttons on the Facebook, Twitter or LinkedIn. These features may collect your internet protocol address (IP address), which webpage you are visiting, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. The use of such features is governed by the privacy policies of the feature owner.

WHILE WE TRY TO ENSURE THAT EVERY THIRD PARTY WHO DISCLOSES PERSONAL DATA TO US HAS YOUR CONSENT TO DO SO, IF YOU BELIEVE THAT A THIRD PARTY HAS INAPPROPRIATELY DISCLOSED YOUR PERSONAL DATA TO US, PLEASE CONTACT THAT THIRD PARTY. IF THEY DO NOT ADEQUATELY RESPOND TO YOUR INQUIRIES, PLEASE LET US KNOW IMMEDIATELY. 

For purposes of maintaining quality service, calls to Dundas BI Support service lines may be recorded. A recorded message given prior to your call being answered will let you know if your call may be the subject of our random call recording quality assurance program. 

#### Google AdWords Remarketing

We use the Google Ads remarketing service to advertise our products and services across the Internet. Through this service, our site places a cookie (see the description of cookies above) on your computer to identify the parts of our site that you visit. This cookie does not identify you; it merely indicates that your computer has visited this part of our site. The Google Ads remarketing service will then display relevant ads to you when you browse the rest of the Internet. 

This service allows us to tailor our marketing to display ads that are relevant to you. Find more information about Google's Ads remarketing service [here](https://support.google.com/adwords/topic/3122875?hl=en&ref_topic=3122874)

Opting Out from Google AdWords Remarketing. You can opt out of our Google AdWords remarketing service at any time by visiting Google's "Ads Settings" [ preferences manager](http://www.google.com/settings/ads?hl=en&sig=ACi0TCj5kCduxSPBl7NytM0VFrGg8gpz6S_O5DEV8-sFvbb5IrJWgZ5VToqtfl-rM_4sB6RJtRc12wZruNC8Wx76bc-a8YUv4-03ptlM6Uqr5_c7YiRLjZ_9-ase2pF6499qaLRbm84sio_DhA7Qu9xn8H-gBb2BGH0n8go_bvfxr_saU4y88xzaJRbiRF7VxsWcFGphnQCZ). You can also opt out of certain third-party vendor's use of cookies by visiting the Network advertising initiative's [opt-out](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) page. 

Information about Google’s privacy policy can be found [here](https://privacy.google.com/#_ga=2.129505422.321627752.1533209074-293734585.1509986970).

####  When Information May be Disclosed to Outside Parties: 

Except as specifically provided for in this Policy, we do not disclose any personal data to third parties. The following are the limited instances where we may disclose your personal data to third parties: 

  * \- to facilitate the processing of your order and delivery of the purchased products and services;
  * \- to investigate potentially fraudulent or questionable activities regarding your account(s) or the use of our products or services;
  * \- to offer you related products and services that might benefit you;
  * \- in anticipation of and in the course of an actual or potential sale, reorganization, consolidation, merger or amalgamation of our business; and
  * \- when required or permitted by law.

The type of information we are legally required to disclose may relate to national security, criminal investigations or government tax reporting requirements. In some instances such as a legal proceeding or court order, we may also be required to disclose certain information to authorities. Only the information specifically requested is disclosed and we take precautions to satisfy ourselves that the authorities that are making the request have legitimate grounds to do so. If your personal data becomes subject to a legal disclosure requirement and we are permitted to do so, we will attempt to notify you of said disclosure, if we have current contact information on file. 

There are some situations where we are legally permitted to disclose personal data such as employing reasonable and legal methods to enforce our rights or to investigate suspicion of illegal activities. 

From time to time, we may post case studies, success stories and testimonials that contain personal data on our website or in other publicly distributed material. In such cases, we obtain your written consent before posting your name or other personal data with the case study, success story or testimonial. If you wish to delete or remove your case study, success story or testimonial, you can contact us at [marketing@dundas.com](mailto:marketing@dundas.com). 

Our website provides customers, partners and users with access to a community forum for questions, comments, and other information. Any information that you post to the forum might be collected and used by others who access it. You may request to have your personal data removed from such forum by contacting us at [marketing@dundas.com](mailto:marketing@dundas.com) . If we cannot remove your information, we will contact you with reasons why.

#### Our Employees and your Personal Information:

In the course of daily operations, access to private, sensitive and confidential information is restricted to authorized employees who have a legitimate business purpose and reason for accessing it. For example, when you call us, our designated employees will access your information to verify who you are and to assist you in fulfilling your requests. 

Unauthorized access to and/or disclosure of personal data by an employee of Dundas is strictly prohibited. All employees are expected to maintain the confidentiality of personal data at all times and failing to do so will result in appropriate disciplinary measures, which may include dismissal. 

#### LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING PERSONAL DATA (APPLICABLE TO EEA ONLY)

If you are located in the European Economic Area (EEA), Dundas’ legal basis for collecting and processing the personal data we receive depends on the context in which it is sent to us. In our normal course of business, we will only collect and process personal data that has been sent to us by you through our website, via email, mail or facsimile. Subject to compliance with the requirements of Article 6 of the GDPR, as of May 25, 2018, we will process the personal data sent to us where you have provided your consent, or where processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or in order to take steps, at your request, prior to entering into a contract. We may also process your personal data where the processing of the information is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the controller or by a third party and not overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms which require protection of personal data, in particular where you are a child. We may process your personal data where we have a legal obligation to collect and process personal data and are the controller in respect of such data, or where the processing is necessary to protect your vital interests or that of another natural person.

In circumstances where we rely on your consent to process the personal data, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. However, this may not affect the lawfulness of the processing based on the consent Dundas has received prior to the withdrawal of consent.

#### How We Safeguard Your Information:

We use industry standard technologies and maintain current security standards to ensure that your personal data is protected against unauthorized access, disclosure, inappropriate alteration or misuse. 

Electronic customer files are kept in a highly secured environment with restricted access. Paper-based files are stored in locked filing cabinets. Access is also restricted. 

We manage our server environment appropriately and our firewall infrastructure is strictly adhered to. Our security practices are reviewed on a regular basis and we routinely employ current technologies to ensure that the confidentiality and privacy of your information is not compromised. 

Our web site uses Secure Socket Layer (SSL) and 256 bit encryption technologies to enhance security when you visit the secured areas of these sites. SSL is the industry standard tool for protecting and maintaining the security of message transmissions over the Internet. When you access your accounts or send information from secured sites, encryption will scramble your data into an unreadable format to inhibit unauthorized access by others. 

To safeguard against unauthorized access to your accounts, you are required to "sign-on" using a user ID and a password to certain secured areas of the Dundas's website. Both user ID and password are encrypted when sent over the Internet. If you are unable to provide the correct password, you will not be able to access these sections. 

#### ACCESSING, AMENDING AND REMOVING YOUR INFORMATION

You may access, verify and amend the information associated with your accounts by logging into your Dundas BI Support account and editing your profile. You may access and verify any of your information, or request to have your account removed by contacting our customer contact center at [+1-416-467-5100](tel:+14164675100) or support@dundas.com Dundas reserves the right to validate requests to ensure legitimacy. . 

To help us keep your personal data up-to-date, we encourage you to amend inaccuracies and make corrections as often as necessary. Despite our efforts, errors sometimes do occur. Should you identify any incorrect or out-of-date information in your file(s), we will make the proper changes. Where appropriate, we will communicate these changes to other parties who may have unintentionally received incorrect information from us. 

#### DATA RETENTION

Dundas will retain your personal data for as long as needed to fulfill the purposes for which the data was provided. Dundas will delete or anonymize your personal data when we no longer have a legitimate business need for it. If it is no longer possible to delete it because, for example, it has been backed up in archives, then we will securely store the personal data and isolate it from further processing until deletion is possible.

For personal data that we process on behalf of customers and partners users, we will retain such personal data in accordance with the terms of our agreement with them, subject to applicable laws. 

#### ADDITIONAL RIGHTS FOR EEA AND CERTAIN OTHER JURISDICTIONS

If you reside in the EEA or certain other jurisdictions, you have the right to exercise additional rights available to you under the local law that applies to you:

  * \- Right of erasure: you may have a broader right to have personal data that we hold about you erased or deleted.
  * \- Right to object to processing: you may have the right to request that Dundas stop processing your personal data.
  * \- Right to restrict processing: you may have the right to request that Dundas limit the processing of your personal data in some circumstances (e.g. where you believe that the personal data we hold about you is inaccurate or was obtained unlawfully).
  * \- Right to data portability: in some limited circumstances, you may have the right to receive a copy of your data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and to request that we transfer your personal data to another controller.

In the event you would like to inquire about exercising these rights, you may contact us at privacy@dundas.com. In order to protect your privacy and that of others, we may take steps to verify your identity and the validity of your request before we comply. 

#### POLICY TOWARDS CHILDREN

We do not knowingly or intentionally collect or process any personal data from children under the age of 13. If a parent or legal guardian becomes aware that their child has provided us with personal data without their consent, they should contact us at info@dundas.com , and we will use reasonable efforts to delete such information. 

#### ASSIGNMENT OR TRANSFER

If Dundas is to sell or divest all or substantially all of our business or assets with another entity, we may assign or transfer this Policy as well as your account and related data (including personal data) in accordance with applicable laws.

#### QUESTIONS, CONCERNS AND COMPLAINTS

If you have a question about the Policy stated on this site, please call us at +1-416-467-5100. If you have a concern or complaint about privacy, confidentiality or the personal data handling practices of Dundas, our employees or service suppliers, please contact: . 

**Irina Bogatch** Privacy Officer  
Phone: [+1-416-467-5100 x120](tel:+14164675100p120)  
Fax: [+1-416-422-4801](tel:+14164224801)  
Email: [privacy@dundas.com](mailto:privacy@dundas.com)

Before Dundas is able to provide you with any information or correct any inaccuracies, however, we may ask you to verify your identity and to provide other details to help us to respond to your request. We will endeavor to respond within an appropriate timeframe. 

#### Updating this Privacy Policy:

Any changes to our privacy policy and information handling practices will be acknowledged in this policy in a timely manner. We may add, modify or remove portions of this policy when we feel it is appropriate to do so. You may determine when this policy was last updated by referring to the modification date found at the bottom of this privacy policy. 

#### Web Sites Governed by this Privacy Policy:

The web site that is governed by the provisions and practices stated in this privacy policy is: [www.dundas.com](https://www.dundas.com/). 

The Dundas web site may contain links to other third party sites that are not governed by this privacy policy. Although we endeavor to only link to sites with high privacy standards, our privacy policy will no longer apply once you leave the Dundas web site. Additionally, we are not responsible for the privacy practices employed by other third party web sites. Therefore, we suggest that you examine the privacy statements of those sites to learn how your information may be collected, used, shared and disclosed. 

#### GOVERNING LAW AND DISPUTE RESOLUTION

This Privacy Policy, and all related matters are governed solely by the laws of the Ontario, Canada and applicable federal laws of Canada, excluding any rules of private international law or the conflict of laws which would lead to the application of any other laws. 

Any claim or cause of action you may have arising from, connected with, or relating to this privacy policy or Dundas's handling of your personal information, or any related matters must be commenced within six (6) months after the claim or cause of action arises, after which time the claim or cause of action is forever barred, regardless of any statute or law to the contrary.
